<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Dayton's Best Real Estate Training</title>
    <description>Denise Swick, a top Real Estate Agent in Dayton, shares her own internal real estate agent training for free. Her Real Estate Training, Tips and Advice will help you sell more homes in less time.</description>
    <link>localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Thu, 09 May 2019 10:20:53 -0500</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 09 May 2019 10:20:53 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.2.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>5 Ways to Get Your Buyers Offer Accepted When There’s Multiple</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/MEBrlqb0aN4?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’re at the time of year where the market is heating up and multiple offers are becoming more and more common. Many agents, including Greg, want to know how to get their offer accepted when there is a multiple-offer situation. &lt;strong&gt;We actually came up with a plan last summer during the hot market and I wanted to share that with you today.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first thing we make sure we do is include a pre-approval letter as opposed to a pre-qualification letter. &lt;strong&gt;A pre-qualificaion doesn’t necessarily mean someone can afford a home.&lt;/strong&gt; With a pre-approval, you have income and asset verification, which gives you a strong indication of your buyer’s finances.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Depending on the type of financing, removing the appraisal contingency may be another option to explore. When going over asking price isn’t enough, this really makes a seller feel good. &lt;strong&gt;Last year, we sold a home for $20,000 above its appraisal price because the contingency was removed.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Reaching out to the seller’s agent is always a wise move.%20localhost:4000/5-ways-to-get-your-buyers-offer-accepted-when-theres-multiple.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Reaching out to the seller’s agent is always a wise move.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next, earnest money is crazy important. It indicates the buyer’s willingness to agree to the terms and conditions in the contract. &lt;strong&gt;We all know that 99% of the time, there are so many conditions and contingencies that there are multiple ways for buyers to back out if something changes.&lt;/strong&gt; The more earnest money you give, the more skin in the game you have, and sellers respect that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What is the one thing that sellers hate when going through inspections? Seeing that long list of inspection items. To combat that, we’ve started writing into our contracts in a way that the inspections are for the buyer’s peace of mind and for health and safety issues only. &lt;strong&gt;This is telling the sellers that you’re not planning on nitpicking the report&lt;/strong&gt;, and unless something is a safety issue, you probably won’t ask to get it fixed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, make sure that you reach out to the seller’s agent. Ask them what their seller wants out of the transaction besides price. This helps you in advance to tailor your offer to what the seller wants. Giving the seller time to move out, for example, can be a huge factor for sellers and could help your buyer win the home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hope these tips were all helpful to you. If you have any questions for me in the meantime, don’t hesitate to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 29 Apr 2019 12:15:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/5-ways-to-get-your-buyers-offer-accepted-when-theres-multiple.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/5-ways-to-get-your-buyers-offer-accepted-when-theres-multiple.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
