<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" xmlns:itunesu="http://www.itunesu.com/feed" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Dayton Real Estate Podcast with Denise Swick</title>
    <link>localhost:4000</link>
    <atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" href="localhost:4000"/>
    <description>If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from Denise Swick & Company - your professional Dayton Real Estate Agents.</description>
    <language>en</language>
    <managingEditor>Denise Swick</managingEditor>
    <lastBuildDate>2019-05-16 13:02:59 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <media:copyright>Denise Swick</media:copyright>
    <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000/img/podcast.jpg"/>
    <media:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Dayton, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</media:keywords>
    <media:category scheme="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd">Education</media:category>
    <itunes:owner>
      <itunes:email>careers@deniseswick.com</itunes:email>
      <itunes:name>Denise Swick</itunes:name>
    </itunes:owner>
    <itunes:author>Denise Swick</itunes:author>
    <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
    <itunes:image href="localhost:4000/img/podcast.jpg"/>
    <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Dayton, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
    <itunes:subtitle>Learn all the tips, tricks and more for buyers and sellers in the Dayton Area Real Estate Market</itunes:subtitle>
    <itunes:summary>If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from Denise Swick & Company - your professional Dayton Real Estate Agents.</itunes:summary>
      <itunes:category text="Education"/>
    
      <item>
        <title>How to Become a Top Agent in the Field</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/how-to-become-a-top-agent-in-the-field.html</link>
        
        <author>Denise Swick</author>
        <pubDate>2019-05-09 12:48:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Denise+Swick/Dayton+Real+Estate+Agent-+How+to+Become+a+Top+Agent+in+the+Field.mp4</guid>
        <description>

There are three key things an agent should do in order to become a top-producer in the industry:

1. Follow a consistent schedule. This is the hardest thing for an independent contractor to do because for them, there’s no one to hold them accountable for coming into work at a specific time or to get any particular results. Even in a regular job, there are certain, measurable things that you have to do every day, and unfortunately, the independent contractor setup takes away a lot of natural accountability. If people wonder why real estate agents don’t have more paychecks, it’s because they’re not following a reasonable schedule that both allows time for their business and their personal lives.

2. Lead-generate consistently. Not everyone likes to pick up the phone and make calls to prospects like a telemarketer, as I have for 20 years. However, there are other forms of lead-generating methods out there. Whatever you choose to do to generate your leads, whether it’s a farm, phone prospecting, or a social media campaign, make sure that you are doing it consistently. For example, if you decide to buy your leads from Zillow, don’t just buy them for one month and then stop because you go too busy. Real estate, like any job, is a funnel—the more you put in, the more opportunities and leads you’ll get back from it.

One of my first business coaches once said, “There are people that you know and people that you don’t know: Which group is bigger?” The group of people that I don’t know is much bigger than the group that I do know, so I had to go out and learn how to talk to people.

“Real estate, like any job, is a funnel—the more you put in, the more opportunities and leads you’ll get back from it.”

3. Constantly and aggressively follow up with leads. Once you learn to talk to people and you start getting leads and opportunities, you have got to follow up on it. Sometimes it can literally take three to seven conversations to get a buyer or a seller to say ‘yes’; depending on where they are in the process, it could take more or less. 

Our definition of a qualified lead is someone who is willing to undergo a transaction with us and wants to do so within the next 30 days. Given that, we have a pretty strict follow-up schedule; we don’t want the dead weight to cloud all of the other golden opportunities that are out there.



Most agents are independent contractors—they’re not on teams, they’re not in an environment that supports accountability. Taking today’s three qualities of a top agent to heart will absolutely help bring your career from failure to success.

If you have any questions or would like to speak more in-depth about this topic, don’t hesitate to reach out to me. I’d love to have a conversation with you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Denise+Swick/Dayton+Real+Estate+Agent-+How+to+Become+a+Top+Agent+in+the+Field.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Denise+Swick/Dayton+Real+Estate+Agent-+How+to+Become+a+Top+Agent+in+the+Field.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>What separates regular agents from top agents? Today I’ll lay out what it takes to make your career more than just average.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Denise Swick</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>What separates regular agents from top agents? Today I’ll lay out what it takes to make your career more than just average.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Dayton, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Dayton Real Estate Agent: Interview | Denise's Story</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/dayton-real-estate-agent-interview-denises-story.html</link>
        
        <author>Denise Swick</author>
        <pubDate>2019-05-09 09:40:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>Hear how Denise Swick built her real estate business in Dayton, her tips for success, and her goals for the future.





</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Hear how Denise Swick built her real estate business in Dayton, her tips for success, and her goals for the future.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Denise Swick</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Hear how Denise Swick built her real estate business in Dayton, her tips for success, and her goals for the future.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Dayton, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>5 Ways to Get Your Buyers Offer Accepted When There’s Multiple</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/5-ways-to-get-your-buyers-offer-accepted-when-theres-multiple.html</link>
        
        <author>Denise Swick</author>
        <pubDate>2019-04-29 12:15:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Denise+Swick/Dayton+Real+Estate+Agent-+How+to+Craft+Your+Buyers+Offers+in+Todays+Market.mp4</guid>
        <description>

We’re at the time of year where the market is heating up and multiple offers are becoming more and more common. Many agents, including Greg, want to know how to get their offer accepted when there is a multiple-offer situation. We actually came up with a plan last summer during the hot market and I wanted to share that with you today.

The first thing we make sure we do is include a pre-approval letter as opposed to a pre-qualification letter. A pre-qualification doesn’t necessarily mean someone can afford a home. With a pre-approval, you have income and asset verification, which gives you a strong indication of your buyer’s finances.

Depending on the type of financing, removing the appraisal contingency may be another option to explore. When going over asking price isn’t enough, this really makes a seller feel good. Last year, we sold a home for $20,000 above its appraisal price because the contingency was removed.

“Reaching out to the seller’s agent is always a wise move.”

Next, earnest money is crazy important. It indicates the buyer’s willingness to agree to the terms and conditions in the contract. We all know that 99% of the time, there are so many conditions and contingencies that there are multiple ways for buyers to back out if something changes. The more earnest money you give, the more skin in the game you have, and sellers respect that.



What is the one thing that sellers hate when going through inspections? Seeing that long list of inspection items. To combat that, we’ve started writing into our contracts in a way that the inspections are for the buyer’s peace of mind and for health and safety issues only. This is telling the sellers that you’re not planning on nitpicking the report, and unless something is a safety issue, you probably won’t ask to get it fixed.

Finally, make sure that you reach out to the seller’s agent. Ask them what their seller wants out of the transaction besides price. This helps you in advance to tailor your offer to what the seller wants. Giving the seller time to move out, for example, can be a huge factor for sellers and could help your buyer win the home.

I hope these tips were all helpful to you. If you have any questions for me in the meantime, don’t hesitate to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Denise+Swick/Dayton+Real+Estate+Agent-+How+to+Craft+Your+Buyers+Offers+in+Todays+Market.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Denise+Swick/Dayton+Real+Estate+Agent-+How+to+Craft+Your+Buyers+Offers+in+Todays+Market.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>What can you do to ensure that your buyers’ offers are accepted? Here’s some quick advice.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Denise Swick</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>What can you do to ensure that your buyers’ offers are accepted? Here’s some quick advice.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Dayton, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
    <copyright>Denise Swick</copyright>
    <media:credit role="author">Denise Swick</media:credit>
    <media:rating>nonadult</media:rating>
    <media:description type="plain">If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from Denise Swick & Company - your professional Dayton Real Estate Agents.</media:description>
  </channel>
</rss>
